<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tops on Innercoder.dev</title>
    <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tops on Innercoder.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jarrocha.github.io/top/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>About I am an expericenced software developer with interest in embedded systems, IoT, RTOS, computer networking, computer vision, navigation systems and controls. I created this website with the intent of both learning and giving back to the community. I hope that the information you find here is helpful. I will try my best to keep the website alive with interesting posts and topics, while also improving on my writing skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/courses/</guid>
      <description>Courses on Embedded Systems, Robotics, and Controls  Here are some courses that I have taken and found to be really good. They are either free or low cost. They all vary in skills from software development, embedded systems, and control systems.
Space Dynamics and Control Coursera Space Dynamics and Control Autonomous Navigation for Flying Robots Coursera Autonomous Navigation for Flying Robots
Robotics Specialization Coursera Robotics Specialization
Modern Robotics Specialization Coursera Modern Robotics Specialization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/upcoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/top/upcoming/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming Topics  I have always considered that teaching is a good learning tool. So I plan to revamped the site with a few good topics involving some good theory mix with actual code results on devices.
Topics will include:   Kernel Drivers on Raspberry Pi and BeagleBone Black  Involved Blocked devices and I2C communication with peripherals. USB drivers   RTOS  Timing sequences differences between Linux-RT and Linux with SCHED_FIFO + affinity settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>