<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Innercoder.dev</title>
    <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Innercoder.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 16:47:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jarrocha.github.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding Your Own Network Sniffer</title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-network-sniffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 16:47:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-network-sniffer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This a small project that came to mind after reading some reference
material while stuyding HTTP. It basically consists of using raw sockets to
make the kernel handle L2 data/frames to the user application. From there
anything is possible, a ping server, a traceroute appication, IP spoofing,
man-in-the-middle attacks, the sky is the limits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capturing Websites With Sockets and HTTP</title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-sockets-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 11:57:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-sockets-http/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post shows a program that captures web pages’s index.html with sockets.
To do this, it creates a TCP client socket, connects to a web server and takes
all the data to stdout. The input supports IPv4, IPv6, and hostname resolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TCP Sockets Server</title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/tcp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 10:47:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/tcp-server/</guid>
      <description>Intro  This post serves as a explanation of the basics of a TCP socket server, which serves as the base to a future post explaining the basics of a web server.
Note: the complete code of an older version is fully posted in the end. Check my github repo for an updated version. Link.
There are good tutorials out there that explain each of the functions of the sockets POSIX API in detail so this post will serve mostly to understand the overall basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming a Linux Shell Terminal</title>
      <link>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-shell-prog-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 10:30:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarrocha.github.io/post/2018-11-18-shell-prog-basics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A shell is an interactive program that in its core forks for new processes and wait for their termination. In other words, we present a prompt, the user enters the commands, we parse the input , and execute it. Good error and signal handling is needed, as well as the return values of the different system calls that we will use. The man pages come real handy for this since we have a very good reference just a terminal screen away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>